Shinji Pons, Senior Product Designer

Toulouse, France +33 07 44 74 31 34 hello@shinjipons.com

Links	Portfolio Website Linkedin Profile				
Summary	I'm a results-driven product designer with 10 years of experience designing complex tools and workflows for desktop 3D applications tailored for creative professionals.				
Areas of Expertise	Product Design User Interface Design 3D Modeling	Figma Blender Autodesk Alias	Python JavaScript HTML/CSS		

Employment History

Jun 2023 - Present

Senior Product Designer at Ragdoll Dynamics

Toulouse, France

I'm the sole designer in this startup that develops software that makes 3D character animation easier thanks to rigid body dynamics. In the past few months, I have:

- Designed Ragdoll's standalone desktop application experience from the ground up
- Contributed to testing and quality assurance effort of the upcoming Ragdoll Dynamics Blender add-on
- Learned to prototype interface elements in the actual desktop application with ImGui exposed via JavaScript

Jan 2021 - May 2023

Senior Experience Designer at Electronic Arts

Guildford, UK

Worked on Frostbite, EA's game engine, to improve its tools and workflows thus giving more than 5000 professionals across all of EA's game studios better ways to create better games. Directly shaping the future of character creation workflows for AAA titles such as Skate. EA FC. and UFC.

- Designed tangible improvements in high quality character workflows for EA Sports & Racing titles on features such as runtime deformation, mass loading and composition of character assets at runtime.
- Designed new editor interaction elements such as manipulators, informed by competitive analysis and user research to define the foundations of the future of the Frostbite game engine.

May 2019 - Dec 2021

Senior Product Designer at The LEGO Group

Billund, Denmark

Modernized LEGO Digital Designer Pro, LEGO's internal 3D software for digital design of LEGO sets and building instructions. Shaped and influenced the entire design and development pipeline of physical LEGO products to become digital-first and more resource-effective.

- Led the design experience for LEGO Digital Designer Pro, by leveraging brick data such as connectivity, pricing and real-time physics simulation to improve the professional lives of over 300 LEGO master designers and building instruction designers.
- Reduced the time consumed by repetitive tasks by up to 90% by designing simple yet sophisticated user-friendly tools and addressing the most pressing needs in the LEGO designer user community.
- Contributed to building a fully digital pipeline from concept design through to marketing material production for 70% of all new LEGO products by sharing technical expertise and personal experience.

Fmploy	ment	History	(cont	inued)

Jun 2017 - May 2019

Experience Designer at Autodesk

Hanover, Germany

Single-handedly directed the design of features and workflows for fast concept modelling and computational design in Alias, the leading 3D CAD software for creating high quality, desirable products in the automotive industry and industrial design.

- Led the design aspect for all of the game-changing subdivision modelling features, tools and workflows released in Alias 2020.
- Validated the workflows of the subdivision modelling tools in Alias by conducting user testing workshops with more than 60 users from world-class automotive design studios such as Volvo and Toyota.
- Designed and delivered tools that let customers deliver concept designs up to three times faster than with the previous version of Alias.

Apr 2016 - Apr 2017

Experience Designer at Thomson Reuters

London, UK

Designed prototypes and features using natural language processing to automate risk detection and reduction inside of the World-Check Risk Intelligence product.

Feb 2015 - Nov 2015

User Experience Designer at Microsoft

London, UK

Designed interactive experiences in branded spaces to increase public awareness of Windows Devices through the use of Microsoft hardware and software.

Education

2010 - 2014 London College of Communication

London, UK

Bachelor of Arts, Graphic & Media Design (First Class Honours)

Languages

French

Native speaker

English

Native speaker

Internships

Sep 2014 - Dec 2014

Graphic Design Intern at Barnbrook

London, UK

Internship at this award winning independent graphic design studio, working for clients such as Art Basel and David Bowie.

Oct 2012 - Jan 2013

Graphic Design Intern at Ateliers Jean Nouvel

London, UK

Internship at this award-winning architecture firm, working on the design of icons and typographic system for the Louvre Abu Dhabi museum.